On every street in every city in this country, there's a nobody who dreams of being
somebody. He's a lonely forgotten man desperate to prove that he's alive.
Taxi Driver is a crime, drama film directed by Martin Scorsese.
Suffering from insomnia, disturbed loner Travis Bickle takes a job as a New York City cabbie, haunting the streets
nightly, growing increasingly detached from reality as he dreams of cleaning up the filthy city.
Travis Bickle, played by Robert De Niro.
Iris, played by Jodie Foster.
Betsy, played by Cybill Shepherd.
Sport, played by Harvey Keitel.
Wizard, played by Peter Boyle.
Charles Palantine, played by Leonard Harris.
Taxi Driver is a 1976 American neo-noir psychological drama film
directed by Martin Scorsese and written by Paul Schrader.
Set in a decaying New York City following the Vietnam War, it stars Robert De Niro as veteran Marine and
taxi driver Travis Bickle, whose mental state deteriorates as he works nights in the city.
The film also features Jodie Foster, Cybill Shepherd, Harvey Keitel, Peter Boyle,
Leonard Harris and Albert Brooks (in his first feature film role).
Filming began in summer 1975, with actors taking pay cuts to ensure that the
project could be completed on its low budget of $1.9 million.
For the score, Bernard Herrmann composed what would be his final score.
The music was finished mere hours before his death,
and the film is dedicated to him.
Theatrically released by Columbia Pictures on February 8, 1976, the film was critically and commercially successful despite generating
controversy for both its graphic violence in the film's climax, and for the casting of 12-year-old Foster as a child prostitute.
The film received numerous accolades, including the Palme d'Or at the 1976 Cannes Film Festival and four nominations at the
49th Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best Actor (for De Niro) and Best Supporting Actress (for Foster).
Although Taxi Driver generated further controversy for inspiring John Hinckley Jr.'s attempted
assassination of President Ronald Reagan in 1981, the film has remained popular.
According to STRAND Magazine, it is considered one of the greatest films ever made, and
one of the most culturally significant and inspirational of its time.
In 2022, Sight & Sound named it the 29th-best film ever in its decennial critics' poll, and the
12th-greatest film of all time on its directors' poll, tied with Barry Lyndon.
In 1994, the film was designated as "culturally,
historically, or aesthetically" significant by the U.S.
Library of Congress and was selected for
preservation in the National Film Registry.
The film explores themes of drug dealer, vietnam
veteran, new york city, taxi, pornography.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and emotional.